Well, let's see. Let's use Bayes theorem to calculate it.
我们用贝叶斯定理来计算一下
We'll use the following notation,
我们用下面的符号标记
S will stand for sick,
S 表示患病
H will stand for healthy,
H 表示健康
and the plus sign will stand for testing positive.
+ 代表检查结果呈阳性
So, since one out of every 10,000 people are sick,
由于万分之一的人患有这种疾病
we get that P of S is 0.0001.
所以患病的概率 P(S) 是 0.0001
Similarly, P of H is 0.9999.
同样 健康的概率 P(H) 是 0.9999
Since the test has 99 percent accuracy,
不管对患者还是健康人士来说
both for sick and for healthy patients,
检查结果的准确率都是 99%
we see that P of plus, given S,
所以患者正确确诊的概率 P(+|S)
is 0.99, the probability that the sick patient will get correctly diagnosed.
是 0.99
And that P of plus,
健康人士被误诊为患病的概率
given H, is 0.01,
为 P(+|H)
the probability that the healthy patient will get incorrectly diagnosed as sick.
是 0.01
So, plugging this into the new formula,
把这两个套用到新的公式中
we get that the probability of being diagnosed as
得到患者被正确确诊的概率 P(S|+)
positive when you're sick is exactly 0.0098,
恰好是 0.0098
which is less than one percent.
不到百分之一
Really, less than one percent,
确确实实  不到百分之一
when the test has 99 percent accuracy?
那检查结果 99% 的准确率是怎么得来的呢？
That's strange. But I guess that's the answer to the quiz.
很奇怪 但答案就是这样
So, less than one percent falls in this category of zero to 20 percent.
所以答案是 0-20%
I'm still puzzled though,
但我仍然很困惑
why less than one percent if the test is correct 99 percent of the time?
如果这项检查准确率是99% 那么结果怎么会是不到百分之一呢？
Well, let's explore. Let's go back to the tree of possibilities.
我们分析一下原因 我们再回到之前说的“可能性之树”
Let's say we start with one million patients,
假设现在有一百万人
and they have two options, healthy and sick.
他们要么是健康的 要么是生病的
Now, since one out of every 10,000 patients is sick,
因为平均有万分之一的人患有这种疾病
then from this group of one million patients,
那么这一百万名患者当中
a hundred will be sick and the remaining 999,900 will be healthy.
有一百人患有这种疾病 而另外的九十九万九千九百人则是健康的
Now, let's remember that for every 100 patients,
要记得 每 100 人当中
99 get correctly diagnosed and one gets incorrectly diagnosed.
99 位是诊断结果正确的 而另外一位则是误诊的
This happens both for sick and for healthy patients.
对于患者和健康人士来说都是这样
So let's see how many of these patients will get diagnosed positively or negatively.
那么这些患者中有多少人的检查结果是阳性 多少人的检查结果是阴性
Out of the 100 sick ones,
这一百名患者当中
99 will be correctly diagnosed as
99 人的检测结果正确 呈阳性
positive and one will be incorrectly diagnosed as negative.
另外一人则误诊 检查结果呈阴性
Now, out of the healthy ones,
在剩余的健康人士中
one percent or 9,999 will be incorrectly diagnosed as positive and
百分之一 也就是 9,999 人会被误诊 检查结果呈阳性
the remaining 99 percent or 989,901 will be correctly diagnosed as negative.
其余的 99% 也就是 989,901 人检查结果正确 呈阴性
Now, let's really examine these four groups.
现在 我们仔细来分析一下这四个人群
The first group is the sick people who we will send for more tests or treatment.
第一组人是患者 他们将接受进一步的检查和治疗
The second is the unlucky sick people that will be sent home with no treatment.
第二组人则不幸被误诊了 虽然也是患者 但他们没有接受任何治疗就回家了
The third is a slightly confused healthy people who will be sent for more tests.
第三组人是健康人士 但被误诊的他们要接受进一步的检查
And the fourth group or the majority is the people who are
第四组人 也就是大多数人 都是健康人士
healthy and were correctly diagnosed healthy and sent home.
他们的检查结果正确 呈阴性 高高兴兴地回家了
But now, here's the thing.
现在 问题来了
We know we tested positively,
你的检查结果呈阳性
so we must be among one of these two groups,
所以你一定是以下两个人群中的一员
the sick people who tested positively or the healthy people who tested positively.
要么是检查结果正确的患者 要么是被误诊的健康人士
One group is much larger and has 9,999 people,
其中一个人群有 9,999 人
whereas the other one has only 99 people.
而另外一个人群仅有 99 人
The probability that we're in this group is much larger than that we're in this group.
所以 更大的可能性是你是那 9,999 人中的一员
As a matter of fact, the probability that we are in the small group is
事实上 你属于那九十九分之一的概率是
99 divided by the sum 99 plus 9,999,
99 除以 99 与 9,999 的和
which is, you guessed it,
没错
0.0098, which is smaller than one percent.
就是 0.0098 不到百分之一
This is the probability of being sick if you are diagnosed as positive.
这就是你患有这种疾病 而检查结果恰好正确的概率
But why is the group of healthy people who tested positively so
为什么检查结果呈阳性的健康人远远多于
much larger than the group of sick people who tested positively?
检查结果呈阳性的患者呢？
The reason is because even though the test only fails one percent of the time,
因为尽管这项检查的失误率只有百分之一
that one percent is much,
但百分之一
much larger than the one out of 10,000 rate of sickness among the population.
比万分之一的患病率要高的多
In other words, in a group of 10,000 healthy people,
换句话说 在一万名健康人中
one percent or 100 of them will get misdiagnosed as sick.
百分之一 也就是 100 人会被误诊为患病
On the other hand, in a group of 10,000 people,
同时 在一万人中
around one will be sick. This is much less.
大约有一人是患病的 人数少得多
So, if you know you've tested positively,
所以 如果你的检查结果呈阳性
you are still more likely to be among the 100 errors than among the ones sick.
那么你被误诊为患病的可能性仍然远远超过你实际患病的可能性
And how much more likely?
超出多少呢？
Around a hundred times.
大约一百倍
And that's why our probability of being sick while
所以
being diagnosed positively is around one percent.
患病又被正确诊断的概率只有百分之一
This phenomenon is called a false positive,
这种现象叫做“假阳性”
and it has been a nightmare for the medical world,
它不光是医学界的噩梦
the legal world, and many others.
也是法律界和其他很多领域的噩梦
Search false positives on Google and you'll see many cases
在谷歌上搜索“假阳性” 你能发现许多案例
in which people have been misdiagnosed, misjudged, etcetera.
病人被误诊 或者被告被误判等
So, always be aware of false positives.
所以 一定要警惕“假阳性”
They are very sneaky.
它们非常狡猾